<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>International Conference on Representation Theory, Mathematical Physics and Integrable Systems</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>05/01/2018</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>04/30/2019</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardAmount>15000</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>03040000</Code>
<Directorate>
<LongName>Direct For Mathematical &amp; Physical Scien</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<LongName>Division Of Mathematical Sciences</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Matthew  Douglass</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>This award supports the participation of US mathematicians in the conference Representation Theory, Mathematical Physics and Integrable Systems to be held June 4-8, 2018 at Centre International de Recontres Mathematiques in Luminy. Talks at the conference will address the latest progress in research at the nexus of representation theory, mathematical physics, and integrable systems, and will formulate open problems that will drive the development in these areas in the coming years. The conference will foster an environment for the establishment of lasting international collaborations between US and foreign researchers. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The conference will cover the latest developments on the interface of noncommutative algebra, differential and algebraic geometry, and perspectives arising from physics. These connections have proven numerous in recent decades, leading to advances like the development of new and powerful knot invariants, new perspectives on enumerative geometry and string theory, and the introduction of cluster algebra and categorification techniques into a broad range of subareas in algebra, geometry and mathematical physics. The conference website is https://conferences.cirm-math.fr/1746.html&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>04/24/2018</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>04/24/2018</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>1803265</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Milen</FirstName>
<LastName>Yakimov</LastName>
<EmailAddress>yakimov@math.lsu.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>04/24/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Andrei</FirstName>
<LastName>Okounkov</LastName>
<EmailAddress>okounkov@math.columbia.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>04/24/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Louisiana State University &amp; Agricultural and Mechanical College</Name>
<CityName>Baton Rouge</CityName>
<ZipCode>708032701</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>2255782760</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>202 Himes Hall</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Louisiana</StateName>
<StateCode>LA</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1264</Code>
<Text>ALGEBRA,NUMBER THEORY,AND COM</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>7556</Code>
<Text>CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOPS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9150</Code>
<Text>EXP PROG TO STIM COMP RES</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
