<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Dimension reduction for high-dimensional high-order data</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>06/01/2018</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>05/31/2021</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardAmount>100001</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>03040000</Code>
<Directorate>
<LongName>Direct For Mathematical &amp; Physical Scien</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<LongName>Division Of Mathematical Sciences</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Yong Zeng</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>High-dimensional, high-order data commonly arise from a wide range of applications, such as neuroimaging, microbiology, bioinformatics, longitudinal studies, and material sciences. These data possess distinct characteristics compared with traditional low-dimensional or low-order data and pose unprecedented challenges to the statistical community. Dimension reduction often becomes the crucial first step in order to better summarize, visualize, and analyze high-dimensional high-order data. One natural approach is to unfold high-order data into matrices, followed by the use of well-established matrix dimension reduction methods. However, such operations often lead to loss of information on the intrinsic data structures and sub-optimal statistical results of subsequent analyses. In addition, the naive generalization of traditional statistical methods to high-dimensional, high-order data is often statistically or computationally infeasible. Therefore, there is a critical need for new high-dimensional high-order data dimension reduction methods.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In this project, the PI plans to develop new theories, methodologies, and computational algorithms to address a series of fundamental problems in high-dimensional, high-order data dimension reduction. The project will be focused on four major areas: (i) a general framework for regularized tensor SVD; (ii) provable regularized tensor decomposition via alternating annealing; (iii) high-order PCA with theoretical guarantees by a new high-order spiked covariance model; (iv) dynamic network community detection via tensor methods.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>05/15/2018</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>05/15/2018</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>1811868</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Anru</FirstName>
<LastName>Zhang</LastName>
<EmailAddress>anruzhang@stat.wisc.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>05/15/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>University of Wisconsin-Madison</Name>
<CityName>MADISON</CityName>
<ZipCode>537151218</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>6082623822</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>21 North Park Street</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Wisconsin</StateName>
<StateCode>WI</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1269</Code>
<Text>STATISTICS</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>8083</Code>
<Text>Big Data Science &amp;Engineering</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9263</Code>
<Text>COMPUTATIONAL SCIENCE &amp; ENGING</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
