<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Support for the 2018 Gordon Research Conference on Photonuclear Reactions at Holderness School in New Hampshire August 5-10, 2018</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>06/15/2018</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>05/31/2019</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardAmount>5000</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>03010000</Code>
<Directorate>
<LongName>Direct For Mathematical &amp; Physical Scien</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<LongName>Division Of Physics</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Allena Opper</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>This award provides support for graduate students and postdocs to attend the 2018 Gordon Research Conference on Photonuclear Reactions, which will be held at Holderness School in Holderness, New Hampshire, August 5 - 10, 2018.  This conference focuses on the physics accessible with electromagnetic probes at US and international facilities, and is especially relevant now that the Thomas Jefferson National Accelerator Facility has begun its 12 GeV era.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Meetings such as these provide a unique opportunity for junior scientists to participate in discussions in an informal atmosphere that allows them to interact easily with senior scientists. For many early career scientists at this community, it is the first international meeting that they attend. The poster session and poster prize also are prime opportunities for young scientists to present and discuss their work, as well as obtaining recognition from the community.  The organizers have committed to broadening participation at the conference to include underrepresented groups and will advertise the conference in wide range of forums and professional societies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>06/12/2018</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>06/12/2018</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>1812408</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Julie</FirstName>
<LastName>Roche</LastName>
<EmailAddress>rochej@ohio.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>06/12/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Ohio University</Name>
<CityName>ATHENS</CityName>
<ZipCode>457012979</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>7405932857</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>108 CUTLER HL</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Ohio</StateName>
<StateCode>OH</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1232</Code>
<Text>Nuclear &amp; Hadron Quantum Chrom</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>7556</Code>
<Text>CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOPS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
