<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>IEEE PerCom 2018 Student Travel Support Request</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>04/01/2018</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>03/31/2019</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardAmount>25000</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>05050000</Code>
<Directorate>
<LongName>Direct For Computer &amp; Info Scie &amp; Enginr</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<LongName>Division Of Computer and Network Systems</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>M. Mimi McClure</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>This proposal is for support of a travel IEEE (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers) PerCom 2014 to be held in Athens, Greece, March 19 - 23, 2018.  The purpose of this trip is to support approximately 15 - 20 students in the field of Pervasive Computing and Communications. PerCom 2018 will provide a leading edge scholarly forum for researchers, engineers, and students alike to share their state-of-the art research and developmental work in the broad areas of pervasive computing and communications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This conference will provide the students with the opportunity to attend presentations of cutting-edge research results representing the state-of-the-art in pervasive computing, systems and applications.  The attendees are offered a diversity of interactive forums, technical sessions, targeted workshops, interesting poster sessions, and exciting demonstrations. Students will have the opportunity to interact with the world's leading researchers in pervasive computing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>03/21/2018</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>03/21/2018</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>1818233</AwardID>
</Award>
</rootTag>
