<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Workshop on Groups, Geometry and Dynamics</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>07/01/2018</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>06/30/2019</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardAmount>40000</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>03040000</Code>
<Directorate>
<LongName>Direct For Mathematical &amp; Physical Scien</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<LongName>Division Of Mathematical Sciences</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Joanna Kania-Bartoszynska</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>A workshop on Groups, Geometry and Dynamics will be held at the Universidad de la Republica in Montevideo, Uruguay from July 27 to July 31, 2018. The workshop will bring together researchers from South America, Europe and the United States. The workshop will foster international collaboration and aid in the dissemination of recent advances. It is an official satellite conference of the International Congress of Mathematicians to be held in  Rio de Janeiro in August 2018. The funding provided will be focused on the support of U.S.-based  early career mathematicians who are in an especially strong position to benefit from exposure to recent advances and a broader mathematical community.  The organizing committee and the principal investigator are committed to funding a diverse group of mathematicians.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This workshop will focus on geometric group theory, Riemannian geometry and dynamics and their  manifold interactions. The workshop will bring together researchers from South America, Europe and  the United States. The workshop will enhance the worldwide dissemination of recent results in these  fields and encourage interaction and collaboration between researchers from these varied mathematical communities. This workshop aims to build on and further develop the connections developed between  the U.S., European and South American mathematical communities in these fields fostered at a very  productive workshop on Geometry of Groups held in Montevideo in April 2016. Further details about the workshop, including a full list of speakers, is available at the conference website: https://ggdworkshop.cmat.edu.uy/&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>06/07/2018</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>06/07/2018</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>1825533</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Richard</FirstName>
<LastName>Canary</LastName>
<EmailAddress>canary@umich.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>06/07/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>University of Michigan Ann Arbor</Name>
<CityName>Ann Arbor</CityName>
<ZipCode>481091274</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>7347636438</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>3003 South State St. Room 1062</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Michigan</StateName>
<StateCode>MI</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1265</Code>
<Text>GEOMETRIC ANALYSIS</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>7556</Code>
<Text>CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOPS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
