<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Temple University Graduate Student Conference in Algebra, Geometry, and Topology</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>05/15/2018</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>04/30/2019</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardAmount>38135</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>03040000</Code>
<Directorate>
<LongName>Direct For Mathematical &amp; Physical Scien</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<LongName>Division Of Mathematical Sciences</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Joanna Kania-Bartoszynska</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>This award supports the Fourth Annual Graduate Student Conference in Algebra, Geometry, and Topology, to be held on June 2-3, 2018 at Temple University. The conference will bring together around 100 graduate students at all levels and from a variety of backgrounds and universities, along with four distinguished plenary speakers that work at the interface of algebra, geometry, and topology. The conference provides a rare opportunity for a large number of early career mathematicians with similar research interests to come together and develop mathematical relationships. In addition, this conference strongly supports interactions between graduate students from different schools, different backgrounds, and different research areas. This gives graduate students the chance to make connections with mathematicians outside of their respective universities and fields of study.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Graduate students will be able to establish these relationships by presenting their work, discussing ideas and asking questions after talks and during social events, and interacting with the plenary speakers. The majority of the talks will be given by graduate students, supplying them with opportunities to practice presenting their research ideas and interests to fellow students. The conference will strive to include a wide range of topics and a variety of speakers, including under-represented minorities in the field, both as participants and speakers. In addition, talks by distinguished plenary speakers will provide insights into how different parts of algebra, geometry, and topology are connected, open research questions of interest, and recent techniques used in groundbreaking work in these fields. Moreover, the organizing committee is driven by the participation of Temple graduate students with faculty support and guidance, providing the students with several professional development opportunities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For further information, see https://math.temple.edu/events/conferences/gscagt/&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>04/26/2018</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>04/26/2018</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>1826362</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>David</FirstName>
<LastName>Futer</LastName>
<EmailAddress>dfuter@temple.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>04/26/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Matthew</FirstName>
<LastName>Stover</LastName>
<EmailAddress>mstover@temple.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>04/26/2018</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Temple University</Name>
<CityName>Philadelphia</CityName>
<ZipCode>191226003</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>2157077547</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>1801 N. Broad Street</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Pennsylvania</StateName>
<StateCode>PA</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1264</Code>
<Text>ALGEBRA,NUMBER THEORY,AND COM</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1265</Code>
<Text>GEOMETRIC ANALYSIS</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1267</Code>
<Text>TOPOLOGY</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>7556</Code>
<Text>CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOPS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
